<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dmsa on [quandrei]</title>
    <link>https://quandrei.github.io/tags/dmsa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dmsa on [quandrei]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://quandrei.github.io/tags/dmsa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Exposed: MIMIC</title>
      <link>https://quandrei.github.io/post/exposed-mimic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quandrei.github.io/post/exposed-mimic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most influential and interesting projects I have ever had the challenge and pleasure of doing, was organizing the end-of-year exhibition for the Computation Art students. This was several years back, when I was in school, and much younger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently decided to update my CV and join the 21st century, so that it can be contained in an online format, and to my dismay, much of the work that went into that project, seems to have been removed/deleted/obliterated. All I can find remaining online, is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://newmediafix.net/daily/?p=1967&#34;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; on some website. The page that contained this archive still &lt;a href=&#34;http://exposed.concordia.ca/&#34;&gt;exists&lt;/a&gt;, but has been revamped to hold my successors&amp;rsquo; organization of their show. No mention of archives, or past shows. As if nothing my team had achieved mattered. We pioneered that society, and built enough resources for them to continue for years to come, and all we had done&amp;hellip; gone. Disappointing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have some of the print media (hard copy&amp;hellip; I know, I know), but it is still a shame that many of the interesting projects are no longer chronicled online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just need to get that off my chest. I&amp;rsquo;m done now. Carry on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>