<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Domain Registrar on [quandrei]</title>
    <link>https://quandrei.com/tags/domain-registrar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Domain Registrar on [quandrei]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://quandrei.com/tags/domain-registrar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hover, the rant</title>
      <link>https://quandrei.com/post/hover-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quandrei.com/post/hover-sucks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is minor rant really, but I have been mildly annoyed with my domain registrar, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hover.com/&#34;&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt;, recently. Several months ago, I inquired whether I would be able to pay in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xe.com/currency/cad-canadian-dollar&#34;&gt;CAD&lt;/a&gt;, instead of being charged in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xe.com/currency/usd-us-dollar&#34;&gt;USD&lt;/a&gt; (and then having my credit card company add a surcharge due to foreign currency conversion). I thought this would be a trivial and easy request to grant since they are a Canadian company, and I am a Canadian citizen, and it would stand to reason we could do business using our nation&amp;rsquo;s legitimate currency. Not only was the answer a no, but the they gave me some bogus reasoning why they couldn&amp;rsquo;t. Furthermore, they implied that I should take my business elsewhere if I was not happy with that policy. So I have, and moved my domains elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sad thing is, they are not the only Canadian company I have dealt with that operate this way. Companies that enjoy many benefits of our great nation, through tax shelters and government grants/subsidies, and yet the locals who support them are treated shabbily. For shame!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>