<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food on [quandrei]</title>
    <link>https://quandrei.github.io/categories/food/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food on [quandrei]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://quandrei.github.io/categories/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Kanako&#39;s Kitchen</title>
      <link>https://quandrei.github.io/post/kanakos-kitchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quandrei.github.io/post/kanakos-kitchen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I found a blog recently about Japanese home cooking, and it seemed intriguing. I am not, by any stretch, an expert but do enjoy cooking from time to time. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying a few of the recipes, and this is what I have prepared so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To note, the soy sauce I used was general purpose Kikkoman soy sauce for all the recipes, which is considered a Koikuchi soy sauce and not an Usukuchi (a point I wasn&amp;rsquo;t clear on from the recipes).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kanakoskitchen.com/2012/07/30/hakusai-tuna-nimono/&#34;&gt;Hakusai and tuna fish nimono:&lt;/a&gt; This is a very simple and easy recipe that came out really well. Easy for any newbie, nice flavor, and good in a pinch, but I think I would have preferred it with minced pork. Will definitely be trying this one again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kanakoskitchen.com/2010/07/19/saba-nitsuke/&#34;&gt;Saba Nitsuke:&lt;/a&gt; This was also a great dish. Although, since I was using 4 filets of mackerel instead of the 2 in the recipe, I doubled the portions for the sauce. I don&amp;rsquo;t think this was necessary in the end, as I had way too much sauce while simmering the fish, and had a hard time reducing it to an acceptable thickness. It was still quite tasty, just wasted ingredients is all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kanakoskitchen.com/2010/07/22/yakinasu/&#34;&gt;Yakinasu:&lt;/a&gt;  I love eggplants. And this recipe had promise, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I executed very well. Fairly simple, but takes patience and time. I only used the katsuobushi as a seasoning, and skipped the ginger. Also, because we were eating several dishes at once, and I had made a plate for each person, I forgot to put some soy sauce on the side for seasoning, which I think would&amp;rsquo;ve complimented this quite well. Overall, the dish was very smokey, and nice, but I felt lacked something to compliment the smokiness. Again, likely due to the absence of soy sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kanakoskitchen.com/2009/11/16/nuta/&#34;&gt;Nuta:&lt;/a&gt; I used &amp;ldquo;white&amp;rdquo; miso paste for this recipe, but can use whichever you prefer. It was quite good, but due to other cooking distractions, I overcooked the green onions slightly. Still quite tasty, and complimented the above mackerel nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with most dishes, I served all of these with Japanese white rice. I highly recommend reading on how to prepare it, because having mediocre rice can really spoil a meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will continue to go through these, and I suggest you do too. Lots to discover on this blog!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>