<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on [quandrei]</title>
    <link>https://quandrei.com/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on [quandrei]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://quandrei.com/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Migration</title>
      <link>https://quandrei.com/post/hugo-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quandrei.com/post/hugo-migration/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In my endeavor to not be bored, and learn new things, I decided to take a step in a new direction, and move my existing &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; blog to &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-hugo:ed8b63f31f6583b3537dd16634107c12&#34;&gt;Why hugo?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There seem to be some obvious advantages out there for using Hugo over Jekyll, but the following reasons are what sold me on the idea:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an excuse to learn me a great good; specifically get started on &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;go-lang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KISS_principle&#34;&gt;KISS&lt;/a&gt; principle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;performance boost from Jekyll (there are numerous articles out there, take your pick)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taxonomy implememtation was dead-simple with a decent theme (lacking in my previous blog version)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easy migration from &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/migrate-from-jekyll/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easily hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&#34;&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--watch&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--theme=theme_name&lt;/code&gt; options when running locally, which are incredibly useful for dynamically observing changes to the site, and testing/vetting out themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;searching-for-a-theme:ed8b63f31f6583b3537dd16634107c12&#34;&gt;Searching for a theme:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a few interesting themes I was debating on, and here were a few of the front-runners:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/lanyon/&#34;&gt;lanyon-hugo&lt;/a&gt;: I felt like I needed something different than my old blog, so this was out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/casper/&#34;&gt;casper&lt;/a&gt;: was not too keen on the menu layout and the blog rendering, and no categories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/detox/&#34;&gt;detox&lt;/a&gt;: no tag filtering for blog posts, no categories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/startbootstrap-clean-blog/&#34;&gt;startbootstrap-clean-blog&lt;/a&gt;: too many errors to count, didn&amp;rsquo;t work out of the box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/purehugo/&#34;&gt;purehugo&lt;/a&gt;: this was a close second, but there was little documentation for setting defaults for things like social networks, and I did not like the fact that the entire blog post is output on the posts page (should be a partial preview imho)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I am not the type to waste time wrangling HTML/CSS, and wanted to get something ported quickly, I finally decided on &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/redlounge/&#34;&gt;redlounge&lt;/a&gt;. The reasons being as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple and clean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mobile/tablet friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easily implement taxonomies (like tags/categories)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easily have access to social media, both for linking to my personal accounts, and for sharing links on posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only thing I do not like is the preview of the blog posts lacks formatting. Not a deal breaker though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;porting-to-hugo:ed8b63f31f6583b3537dd16634107c12&#34;&gt;Porting to Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The migration tool provided by Hugo did most of the heavy lifting. It was literally as simple as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ hugo import jekyll src_folder_of_jekyll_blog dest_folder
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I cleaned out a few folders I didn&amp;rsquo;t need (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/overview/source-directory/&#34;&gt;Hugo folder structure&lt;/a&gt; for guidance), I just &lt;code&gt;git cloned&lt;/code&gt; a few themes in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;code&gt;dest_folder/themes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and then ran the following to test/vet changes/themes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ hugo serve -w --theme=theme_name
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most time-consuming part was actually doing some light editing on the existing blog posts I already had. I just changed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content/front-matter/&#34;&gt;front-matter&lt;/a&gt; section on blog posts to make it compliant with &lt;code&gt;.toml&lt;/code&gt; structure, looked through my changes to make certain everything looked good, and I was set to start on deploying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For deployment, there are quite a few tutorials out there, if you just look for them, but the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/#hosting-personal-organization-pages:fcefb200141ace3e7bfd6542457b7a72&#34;&gt;Hugo documentation&lt;/a&gt; that I followed pretty much sums up what you need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;issues:ed8b63f31f6583b3537dd16634107c12&#34;&gt;Issues:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only issue I ran into was the CSS not rendering properly after deployment. This was not specifically due to Hugo actually, but because of the fact that I force using &lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt; on my site, through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cloudflare.com/&#34;&gt;Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt;, and use an SSL certificate setup through their panel. The Hugo documentation specifies using your github organization URL as your base URL in your config settings (i.e. &lt;code&gt;username.github.io&lt;/code&gt;). So, when serving up the CSS, the browser displays a message saying the CSS content is not secure, and will not serve up mixed content (unless the end user allows it). All that was needed was changing my base URL in my config to &lt;code&gt;quandrei.com&lt;/code&gt; and I was good to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts:ed8b63f31f6583b3537dd16634107c12&#34;&gt;Final thoughts:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy with the end result. Nice looking/improved site, easy management through git/github, performance-centric. No regrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now if I can only figure out how to get it to write Magento code&amp;hellip; and do my laundry&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;d be set.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Pages Launch</title>
      <link>https://quandrei.com/post/github-pages-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quandrei.com/post/github-pages-launch/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So the process was slow­moving (due to a few other things going on in my life), but it is finally up and running. A few things to take note of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;deciding-on-a-jekyll-theme:2c26a5b1b5753de0d42116532c98c907&#34;&gt;Deciding on a Jekyll theme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was more challenging than I thought. There are quite a few out there, but I decided on one that was simple, and looked slick, namely, &lt;a href=&#34;http://getpoole.com/&#34;&gt;Poole&lt;/a&gt; (the Jekyll butler) using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lanyon.getpoole.com/&#34;&gt;Lanyon&lt;/a&gt; theme. &lt;a href=&#34;http://hyde.getpoole.com/&#34;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt; was a close second, but I preferred having the hidden menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-css-is-a-bit-buggy:2c26a5b1b5753de0d42116532c98c907&#34;&gt;The CSS is a bit buggy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does not seem to be completely cross­browser friendly. I noticed that clicking on the menu icon (top­right) in FF will still have the icon super­imposed on the text, whereas in other browsers, it will move left when displaying the menu (as it should). When using a fresh Jekyll install locally, with no content changed, this is not the case, but as soon as I changed something, it broke for some reason. It&amp;rsquo;s possible I borked something somewhere, but haven&amp;rsquo;t looked into it much. Funny enough, it works nicely on my Nexus 4 using the FF browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;moving-content:2c26a5b1b5753de0d42116532c98c907&#34;&gt;Moving Content&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this was a little dull as I needed to grab the raw content from my SS site, and format it for markdown. SS doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an API I&amp;rsquo;m aware of for such a task (although I didn&amp;rsquo;t look into it much), and I probably could&amp;rsquo;ve written a script for this, but I would&amp;rsquo;ve needed to go through the content anyway to ensure everything was pristine. The script would&amp;rsquo;ve likely taken more time than actually going through the few blog posts I had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-few-nice-things:2c26a5b1b5753de0d42116532c98c907&#34;&gt;A few nice things&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few easily­ done things I liked about SS. One was having a tag cloud, which requires some plugin for Jekyll. Not sure if having a plugin is something I could do on Github Pages, so I would need to look into it. Another, was having a gallery of some photography I did in a past life. Again, a plugin is the likely route, and not sure if gh­pages blah blah blah&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;­­­&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s it. As a treat, I think everyone should read this: &lt;a href=&#34;http://chiefobrienatwork.com/&#34;&gt;Chief O&amp;rsquo;Brien at Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Pages Transition</title>
      <link>https://quandrei.com/post/github-pages-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quandrei.com/post/github-pages-transition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to make the transition from SquareSpace to &lt;a href=&#34;http://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few reasons for this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gh-pages is available for the low, bargain-basement price of free as opposed to SS costing money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gh-pages allows me to version-control my site &amp;ndash; being an avid developer, this appeals to me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gh-pages has the basic features I need &amp;ndash; all I really do is put up links to my projects and blog, and gh-pages allows me to do this easily. SS offers many more features, like e-commerce, but when unused, seems silly to pay for them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the longer I stay with SS, the more difficult it will be to move away from them (i.e. move my content somewhere else, if I ever wish to leave)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the UI in SS seems to be a bit more cumbersome lately, and is starting to annoy me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be moving my content gradually to my new digs: &lt;a href=&#34;http://quandrei.github.io/&#34;&gt;quandrei.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[End transmission]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>