<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming Languages on [quandrei]</title>
    <link>https://quandrei.com/tags/programming-languages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming Languages on [quandrei]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://quandrei.com/tags/programming-languages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Me a Great Good</title>
      <link>https://quandrei.com/post/learn-me-a-great-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quandrei.com/post/learn-me-a-great-good/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;php-we-all-fall-down:fcf46d4111ed7ad22f5a93671cb90cbf&#34;&gt;PHP, we all fall down&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So PHP has been getting me down lately, and I have been looking for the next new thing to get my mojo rising. Despite some improvements that came out of &lt;a href=&#34;http://php.net/manual/en/migration70.new-features.php&#34;&gt;PHP7&lt;/a&gt; and dependency tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://getcomposer.org/&#34;&gt;Composer&lt;/a&gt;, there are a great many things that make day-to-day development, well, annoying. Among them, they include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an identity crisis, where it adopts the verbosity of Java in many of its bloated frameworks, but also retains its procedural style from its C-like hay day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a lack of types, causing unpredictability and a debugging nightmare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;natural assumptions regarding built in functions seem to take a holiday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the fact that its used considerably on the web, and everybody&amp;rsquo;s cousin is learning just enough to be dangerous, I often encounter terrible code I have the pleasure of supporting/maintaining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wordpress and Drupal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If &amp;ldquo;Why PHP sucks&amp;rdquo; is a topic that interests you, some fair points can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://webonastick.com/php.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://whydoesitsuck.com/why-does-php-suck/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-what-next:fcf46d4111ed7ad22f5a93671cb90cbf&#34;&gt;So what next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a few things over the past few months that may have some promise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/&#34;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/&#34;&gt;Rails&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - easy to get a web app up and running, through Rails&amp;rsquo; generators/scaffolding and Ruby&amp;rsquo;s expressiveness. Although, I need to learn more about how the underpinnings work, since the automagically generating everything doesn&amp;rsquo;t sit well with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;http://flask.pocoo.org/&#34;&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - simple/clean syntax, and the flexibility of being a general purpose language, has made learning python a great asset to my toolset. Flask gave me the flexibility I needed to get the job done, with the option to import what I wanted, without a ton of bloat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - the most interesting option so far, as it has numerous features that appeal to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;statically typed, compiled language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;concise/clean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;concurrency baked-in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;comprehensive standard library (without the need for additional tools to get things done)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few months, I will be working with Go quite a bit (it being one of the core development languages at my new digs) and am really excited to get more proficient with it. Hopefully, a quote I heard a number of years ago, doesn&amp;rsquo;t ring true:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never fall in love with a language. It will always break your heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>